umcu.org 2009-05-14

# University of Michigan Credit Union

## **PRIVACY NOTICE TO MEMBERS**

**University of Michigan Credit Union and Affiliates**

This notice is for your information. No response is required.

University of Michigan Credit Union values member privacy and has strict policies and procedures to protect member information from being disclosed to unauthorized parties. This notice describes our privacy policy and how the Credit Union and any affiliated credit union service organizations ("Affiliates") treat the information we receive about you. This notice refers to the Credit Union and its Affiliates by using the terms "us," "we" or "our." 

###  Why We Collect and How We Use Information:

We collect and use non-public personal and public personal information ("information") about you for business purposes with respect to our financial and other business relationships involving you. These business purposes include evaluating applications we receive from you for our products and services, processing your transactions with us, and reviewing your product and service relationships with us. 

### How We Collect Information:

We get most information directly from you. The information you give us when applying for our products and services generally provides the information we need. If we need to verify information or need additional information, we may obtain information from third parties such as adult family members, employers, and consumer reporting agencies. 

### What Information We Collect: 

We collect information about you that relates to your finances, employment, credit history, and transaction history with us or with others, including our Affiliates. Information we receive about you may include your name, address, social security number, assets, and income. Information about your transactions with us may include your account balance, payment history, credit card usage, and credit history. 

### How We Protect Information: 

We treat information in a confidential manner. Our employees are required to protect the confidentiality of information. Employees may access information only when there is an appropriate reason to do so, such as to process transactions or offer our products and services. We also maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect information and these safeguards comply with all applicable laws. Employees are required to comply with our established policies and procedures. When we share information with third party companies to provide products or services, we require the third party to agree that they will keep your information confidential and only use the information for the specified purpose. 

We recognize that protecting children's identities and online privacy is important. Currently, University of Michigan Credit Union does not collect personal information from children under 13 years old through its Young Members web pages, nor does it set "cookies." Cookies are bits of information stored by a Web server on your computer's hard drive that record online activities. 

In the future, if University of Michigan Credit Union decides to collect information from your child who is under 13 years old through the Young Members web pages, we will request your authorization first, in accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. If you have questions concerning the privacy of your child's personal information, please contact us at 1-800-968-8628 or write to us at P.O. Box 7850, Ann Arbor, MI 48107\. 

###  Information Disclosure: 

We may disclose any information when we believe it necessary for the conduct of our business, or where disclosure is permitted by law. For example, information may be disclosed to others to enable them to provide business services for us, such as performing administrative activities for us or assisting in processing a transaction requested by you. Information may also be disclosed for audit or research purposes or to law enforcement and regulatory agencies. We might do this, for example, to help prevent fraud. Information may also be disclosed to our Affiliates as well as others that are outside the Credit Union, such as companies that process data for us and consumer reporting agencies. 

We may provide information to marketing companies to assist us in offering our products and services to you and to financial service companies with which we have a joint marketing agreement. We may share information with third party companies that may offer you products or services on our behalf, such as financial services providers (e.g. insurance companies) or non-financial companies or non-profit organizations. We may make other disclosures of information as permitted by law. We do not disclose any information about former members, except as required by law.

### Non-Disclosure Option: 

If you prefer that we do not disclose information about you to third parties that are not affiliated with us (other than disclosures permitted by law), you may opt out of those disclosures. That is, you may direct us not to make those disclosures. If you wish to opt out of such disclosures, you may do so by calling toll free at 800-968-8628.
